好吧，让我们开始吧欢迎回来这是精简版的第七讲
okay let's get started welcome back this
is the seventh lecture of the condensed
在上一堂课程中，我们介绍了一个非常重要的简单
matter course in the last lecture we
introduced a rather important simple
一维振动的质量单调谐波链链模型
model of vibrations in one dimension the
monotonic harmonic chain chain of masses
和弹簧每个弹簧都一样每个质量都一样极其简单
and Springs every spring is the same
every mass is the same extremely simple
模型，但是它为我们引入了很多非常重要的概念
model but it introduced a lot of very
important concepts to us we solved for
当我们量化系统时，链的所有正常模式
all of the normal modes of the chain
when we quantize the system we
通过对正常模式的量化发现了声子的含义
discovered the meaning of phonons with
the quantization of normal modes were we
介绍了水晶动量的概念，如果你转移一个想法
introduced the concept of crystal
momentum the idea that if you shift a
通过2 pi的波向量，您将获得与您相同的精确物理波
wave vector by 2 pi over a you get back
the same exact physical wave that you
首先，我们介绍了在k空间中布置青铜的概念
started with we introduced the concept
of a bronze own arranged in k space
通常取自2个PI的负PI，其中所有波矢都在
usually taken from minus PI over a 2 PI
over a where all of the wave vectors are
身体上不同的波浪，如果您走出布鲁恩斯区，就可以开始
physically different waves and if you go
outside the Bruins zone you just start
重复您已经描述的波浪，我们也设法
repeating the waves that you've already
described and we also managed to
精确计算该链的热容，然后将其与
calculate the heat capacity of this
chain exactly and we compared it to the
我们以前看过的德拜理论和爱因斯坦理论之一
Debye theory and the Einstein theory
that we had looked at previously now one
我们用于此模型的简化假设是
of the simplifying assumptions we used
going into this model was that every
链中的单个质量和每个弹簧都是相同且真实的
single mass and every single spring in
this chain were the same and in real
材料通常具有不同类型的原子，例如钠
materials you typically have different
types of atoms for example in sodium
氯化物，你将有一个钠原子和一个氯原子，这些将是
chloride you'll have a sodium atom and a
chlorine atom and these will be
不同，所以也许更好的典型材料模型看起来会有些变化
different so maybe a better model of a
typical material would look something
像这样，我在绘制一个深色原子时会有一个浅色原子
like this you'd have a light-colored
atom in a dark colored atom I'm drawing
一维的一切，然后是暗的浅色原子
everything in one dimension again and
then a light colored atom in a dark
彩色的原子和深色的灯杆，等等
colored atom and a light pole down the
dark color down and so forth let me
介绍一些有用的术语，单位单元格的概念是
introduce some nomenclature that's gonna
be useful the idea of a unit cell is the
重复重复的图案，例如，我们可以将这个单元格放在这个盒子里，
repeated repeated motif so for example
we can take our unit cell this box and
如果您一遍又一遍地重复此框，并且将框堆叠在一起而没有
if you repeat this box over and over and
you stack the boxes together with no
您之间的空间将重建整个链条另一个重要的词
space in between you will reconstruct
the entire chain another important word
我们上次介绍的是晶格常数，我们定义为
that we introduced last time
is lattice constant which we defined as
我们通常称之为a，我们将其定义为距离之间的距离
what we usually call it a and we defined
it as the distance between distance
在我们等价的原子之间，例如，像这样的晶格常数
between we equivalent atoms so for
example lattice constant like this we'll
从这个像把原子变成这个浅色原子这样称呼它
call it a from this like put atom to
this light color atom you may also
请注意，晶格常数也恰好是晶胞的大小
notice that that lattice constant also
happens to be the size of the unit cell
像这样的距离，如果我正确驾驶，现在也是一侧
like this this distance here is also a
if I drove properly it was now one side
评论是，左边的晶胞实际上不是唯一的，让我画
comment is that the left the unit cell
is actually not unique let me draw
我还可以同样好地画出该链的另一幅图
another picture of this chain I could
have drawn the unit cell equally well
这样，所以我们甚至应该写下来，因为
like this so that's something we should
probably even write down because it's
重要的晶胞不是唯一的，如果我选择这是一个晶胞，我可以
important unit cell not unique and if I
had chosen this is a unit cell I could
将这些重复项堆叠在一起，并同样构建整个链
stack duplications of that together and
build up the entire chain just as well
现在，我们今天将要进行的实际计算是尝试
now what we're going to do today in a
real calculation is we're going to try
计算看起来像这样的链的火车的正常模式
to calculate the normal modes of a train
of a chain that looks like this and the
我们这样做的原因不仅仅是增加我们已经存在的问题的复杂性
reason we're doing this is not just to
add complexity to a problem we already
实际上是通过在链中具有不同类型的原子来解决的
solved last time in fact by having
different types of atoms in our chain
我们将看到一些根本不同的东西
we're going to see that some
fundamentally new and different things
发生所以这就是为什么这就是我们这样做的原因，所以让我画出这样的链条
occur so that's why that's why we're
doing it so let me draw the chain this
被称为交替链
is known as the alternating chain
通常被称为交替链，有时会注意到双原子
frequently known as the alternating
chain sometimes notice the diatomic
链，看起来像这样，有一个
chain
and it looks kind of like this there's a
黑暗的亚当，然后是光的亚当，黑暗的亚当，然后是光的亚当，黑暗的亚当，是光
dark Adam then a light Adam dark Adam
and a light Adam the dark Adam a light
亚当，他们与斯普林斯相连，依此类推
Adam they're connected together with
Springs and so forth
我们有一个晶格常数a，它是相同的
and we have a lattice constant a which
is the distance between identical you
看到明暗之间的差异已经足够清晰了
see the difference between the light and
dark have made clear enough you can see
好的，所以a是等效原子之间的距离，所以光是亚当之间
that okay so a is the distance between
equivalent atoms so between light Adam
和光亚当，现在我们可以选择我们要写下的模型
and light Adam and now we have a choice
as to what model we want to write down
人们在解决这两个方面有两个共同的选择
and there's two common choices that
people make in solving these two
单独的问题，但它们相似，经常做出的一个选择是
separate problems but they're similar
one choice is frequently made is to make
亮原子的质量暗原子的质量不同我们不会去
the mass of the light atom the mass of
the dark atom different we're not going
解决您可以实际解决的典型家庭作业
to solve that you can actually solve
that for homework that one is a typical
选择我们要解决的是，我们要使两个不同
choice what we're gonna solve instead is
we're going to make the two different
今年春天的首都一号泉和今年春天的卡帕二号泉，我们
Springs this spring Capital One and this
spring Kappa two different and we're
让他们来回交替kappa 1 kappa 2 kappa 1 kappa 2等等
gonna let them alternate back and forth
kappa 1 kappa 2 kappa 1 kappa 2 and so
第四，因此命名为交替链，因为弹簧交替
forth and hence the name alternating
chain because the springs alternate
在资本一和卡伯之间到这两个链的物理
between capital one and Kappa to the
physics of these two chains whether
我们让群众交替或弹簧交替是极端
we're letting the masses alternate or
the springs alternate is extremely
非常相似，我们之所以这样做，是因为它是代数的
extremely similar the reason we're doing
this one is because it's algebraically
只是比您要做的要容易一些
just slightly easier to keep track of
than the one you're going to do for
作业在代数上稍微复杂些，所以让我们写下来
homework which is slightly algebraically
more complicated so let's write down
一些坐标，例如，让我们让浅色原子具有
some coordinates so for example let's
let the light colored atoms have
XN位置和深色原子的位置为Y n，所以让我们
positions X N and the dark colored atoms
have position Y n so for example let's
让这个为x1这个为y1这个为X 2这个为Y 2等等
let this one be x1 this one will be y1
this one be X 2 this will be Y 2 and so
现在，我们解决这类质量和弹簧问题的方法
forth and now the way we solve problems
like this these mass and spring problems
你是从写下牛顿的运动方程开始的，好吧，我
is you start by writing down Newton's
equations of motion so well okay I
应该再指出一个定义Delta X和Delta Y
should point one more definition the
Delta X and Delta Y
平衡创造的偏离平衡位置的偏离
deviations from equilibrium creations
from equilibrium position from from
平衡好了，我们将用以下公式写下牛顿方程
equilibrium okay and we're gonna write
down Newton's equations in terms of
这些Delta X和Delta Y，所以也许也许我会把它放在另一个
these Delta X and Delta Y so maybe
actually maybe I'll put it on another
另一块板在这里，所以质量Delta X双点
another board here
so mass Delta X double dot
质量乘以加速度等于我们在X上必须要小心一点
mass times acceleration equals we have
to be a little bit careful here on X
一个轻原子在其右边具有Kappa 2 Kappa 2，然后在其右侧
atom a light atom on the right it has a
Kappa 2 Kappa 2 and then on the right of
X原子是具有相同数字的ay原子，所以Delta Y和负Delta X n
an X atom is a y atom with the same
number so Delta Y and minus Delta X n
然后在左边是大写字母加资本一，在左边是
and then on its left is a capital one
plus Capital One and on its left is a
指数低一的Delta Y原子是Delta X n每个人都同意吗
Delta Y atom with the index one lower is
Delta X n does everyone agree with that
X 2的左边是y 1，所以我必须大写一个弹簧
that on the left of X 2 is y 1 so I have
to the capital one spring has the lower
索引是好高兴好吧好然后Delta Y和双点好
index yes good happy all right good
and then and Delta Y and double dot okay
因此在a的右边，为什么索引号为高的X是一个
so on the right of a why is an X with
the index one higher and that's a
大写一个春天，所以Delta X n加1减去Delta YN并在左Kappa上
Capital One spring so Delta X n plus 1
minus Delta Y N and on the Left Kappa
Y左边的两个是X 1，因此它是相同索引Delta X的X
two on the left of Y one is X 1 so it's
an X for the same index Delta X and
减去Delta Y，我想我没事，所以这是我们的等式
minus Delta Y and I think I got that
right ok so those are our equations of
运动和解决问题的方式与我们上次所做的方式相同
motion and the way we're going to solve
this is the same way we did last time we
会在Zods的Zots wave上写下一波
will write down a wave on Zots
wave on Zod's so there's some
圆点这个词在德语中实际上是什么意思，而我实际上是不同意
disagreement on what the word on dots
actually meant in german and i actually
所以有人在演讲后拦住了我，一位德语发言者说不，不，你是对的
so someone stopped me after lecture a
german speaker said no no you were right
关于点的意思，然后别人说不，不，你错了
about what on dots means and then
someone else said no no you're wrong
然后我问了几个德国人，他们都不同意，然后
and then I asked a couple German
speakers and they all disagreed and then
实际上有人指出anzats实际上是一个英文单词
actually someone pointed out that anzats
is actually an English word it's in the
OED，您可以查找它，这意味着数学上的猜测，所以我会这样
OED you can look it up it means it means
mathematical guess so so I'm gonna so
在那里真的很好，所以无论如何我们都要写下我们的
it's in there it really is okay so
anyway we're going to write down our
在点上波动，因此Delta xn对I Omega t减去IK以及a和
wave on dots so Delta xn is some a n e
to the I Omega t minus I K and a and
Delta yn会混淆这是怎么称呼ax和I e到I Omega t
Delta yn is oopss how that's called to
ax rather and a Y e to the I Omega t
减去IK和a，我们上次真正指的是
minus I K and a and what we really mean
as last time is where we mean to
实际上占据了整个表达的真正部分，因此
actually take the real part of this
whole expression and because of that
我们可以选择Omega大于零，但K可以是
we're allowed to choose Omega greater
than equal to zero but K can be either
在任一符号上签名以表示现在向左或向右波浪
sign either sign to represent either
left going or right going waves now as
上次我们意识到，如果您取K，然后将其转换为K加2 pi
with last time we realized that if you
take K and you shift it to K plus 2 pi
超过一个，您会返回完全相同的波浪，其原因是因为
over a you get back exactly the same
wave and the reason for that is because
如果您查看指数系数e到负IK加2 pi的倍数
if you look at the exponential factor e
to the minus I K plus 2 pi over a times
n是IK的一遍乘以n等于IK的e完全相同
n is times a times a times n is equal to
exactly the same thing as e to the I K
以及那两个完全相同的匹配项，因此，如果您将K移2 pi
and a matches that those two are exactly
the same so if you shift K by the 2 pi
超过一个，您获得完全相同的波形，但实际上我们很重要
over a you get back exactly the same
wave form rather important in fact we
上次发现只是另外两件事，我们将定期使用
found out last time just a couple other
things we're going to use periodic
边界条件周期边界论文我们使用长度为L的系统
boundary conditions periodic boundaries
theses we use a system of length L
等于n乘以a，所以这意味着我们有n个晶胞晶胞，如果我们有一个
equals n times a so this means we have n
unit cells unit cells and if we have a
L大小的系统，这意味着案件必须处于周期性边界条件
system of size L that means the case
must be on a periodic boundary condition
必须是L乘以P的2 PI，其中P是整数，因此间距
must be 2 PI over L times P where P is
an integer so the spacing
在不同的L之间，K的不同可能值是L上的两个PI
between different L different possible
values of K are two PI over L so now if
我们要计算不同情况的数量，我们进行了完全相同的计算
we want to count the number of different
case we did exactly the same calculation
上次不同情况等于两个PI的可能情况范围
last time different case that equals the
range of possible case that's two PI
在开始重复之前，您可以在a上移动两个PI并得到
over a before we start repeating since
you can shift by two PI over a and get
以相同的方式返回，k之间的间隔是L上的两个PI
the same way back and the spacing
between k's is two PI over L that gives
我们在a或n上获得L，因此不同Ches的数量
us L over a or n so the number of
different Ches
等于系统中单位晶胞的数量
is equal to the number of unit cells in
the system a rather general rule that we
会使用很多次，所以考虑到我们的波浪点，我们可以解决这个问题
will use many times okay so given our
wave on dots up there we can solve this
牛顿方程组是通过插入并做一点点
set of Newton's equations it's by
plugging in and doing a little bit of
代数，然后我承认我要做的代数有点
algebra and then I concede that the
algebra I'm about to do is a little bit
凌乱，但请忍受我，所以这里首先我们要为Delta xn插入，所以两个
messy but bear with me so here goes
first we'll plug in for Delta xn so two
导数给我减去Omega平方M，则波是I Omega t的轴心
derivatives gives me minus Omega squared
M then the wave is ax e to the I Omega t
减去IK和a，等于好就等于Kappa 2倍Delta Y n
minus I K and a and that equals well
okay equals Kappa 2 times Delta Y n
这就是为什么e等于I Omega t减去IK，而a然后让我们做另一个
which is a why e to the I Omega t minus
I K and a and then let's do the other
资本，让我们在另一个y词上做另一个词，所以加上
capital let's do the other term over
here the other y term so that's plus
I Omega t减去IK的大写字母e，然后是n减去1 a，因为它是
Capital One e to the I Omega t minus I K
and then it's n minus 1 a because it's
指数n减去1，然后让我们做2个X项，所以我们有减去Capital 1
an index n minus 1 and then let's do the
2 X terms so we have minus Capital 1
加上Kappa 2a X哎呀，我在这里错过了一个Y，不是I Omega t的一个斧头
plus Kappa 2a X oops I missed an a Y
here didn't I a Y ax e to the I Omega t
减去IK，每个对此都感到满意的人，我都做了正确认识的Jex
minus I K and a everyone happy with that
did I do that correctly known Jex seems
工作正常，然后另一个方程式是减去Ω的平方M，为什么e到I
work okay and then the other equation is
minus Omega squared M a why e to the I
Omega t减去IK和一个等于，让我们先做两个x项，
Omega t minus I K and a equals and let's
do the two x terms first so we have
大写1轴e到I Omega t减去I K，然后是第二个系数
capital 1 ax e to the I Omega t minus I
K and then the coefficient in the second
DX的索引方程（大写为1）有n加1，所以它是n加
equation of the the index of DX with
capital one has n plus 1 so it's n plus
1 n在这里，然后我们得到Iωt减去IK的+ kappa 2轴e和a和
1 n here and then we have + kappa 2 ax e
to the I Omega t minus I K and a and
然后是2个上限，然后是两个Y项减去资本1加Kappa 2a Y e
then the 2 cap then the to the two Y
terms minus capital 1 plus Kappa 2a Y e
等于IΩ减去IK，关于该方程式值得注意的是
to the I Omega t minus I K and a a
notable thing about this equation is
这是我全年要写在黑板上的最长方程
it's the longest equation I'm going to
write on the chalkboard all year long
现在完成了，所以我们不必再做一次，但是实际上
and now it's done so we never have to do
that again but it's not actually
看起来很复杂，因为有很多指数因素
complicated as it might look because
there's a bunch of exponential factors
他们退出了双方取消，所以我们有两个方程，我们可以
which drop out they cancel on both sides
so we have two equations and we can
简化成一个矩阵方程
simplify it into one matrix equation
我将这样写，减去M Omega平方乘以向量ax ay等于
I'll write it this way minus M Omega
squared times the vector ax a y equals
一些大矩阵乘以向量ax到Y，大矩阵是什么
some big matrix times the vector ax a Y
and the big matrix is what is it it's a
减去资本1加Kappa 2，然后减去资本1加Kappa 2
minus Capital 1 plus Kappa 2 and then
minus Capital 1 plus Kappa 2 on the
对角Kappa 1加Kappa 2，然后关闭对角线具有Kappa 2加
diagonal Kappa 1 plus Kappa 2 and then
the off diagonal has Kappa 2 plus
IK a的大写1 e就是那部分指数没有取消
Capital 1 e to the I K a that's that
part of the exponential didn't cancel it
来自加号1，然后是Kappa 2加资本一减IK a
comes from the plus 1 and then the Kappa
2 plus Capital One the minus I K a
从指数中的负1出来的每个人都很好
coming from the minus 1 in the
exponential is everyone good with that
好吧，好的，这是一个特征值
agree ok all right
so what is this this is an eigenvalue
等式中，这个人的特征值减去M Omega平方，
equation where the eigenvalue is this
guy over here minus M Omega squared and
解决特征值方程的方法是将M Omega平方移至
the way you solve an eigenvalue equation
is by moving the M Omega squared to the
对角线在这边，然后将行列式设置为0，
diagonals over on this side then you set
the determinant equal to 0 you get the
特征行列式或特征方程式，有时
characteristic determinant or
characteristic equation or sometimes
如果我们做到这一点，则称为世俗方程式
called the secular equation if we do
that the one-step M Omega squared minus
大写1加Kappa 2的平方除以Kappa 2加大写One e到PI K a
Capital 1 plus Kappa 2 all squared minus
Kappa 2 plus Capital One e to the PI K a
绝对值平方等于0，我们可以很快解决这一问题。
absolute value squared equals 0 and we
can solve that rather rapidly M Omega
平方等于资本1加Kappa 2加上或减去绝对值Kappa 2
squared equals capital 1 plus Kappa 2
plus or minus absolute value Kappa 2
再加上资本1 e到i pi K a，这就是我们的解决方案
plus Capital 1 e to the I pi K a and
that's our solution now one thing you
可能会注意到，对于每个K，欧米茄都有两种可能的解决方案
may notice is that for each K there are
two possible solutions of Omega the plus
解决方案中的负解正确，这样就可以在这里写下
solution in the minus solution right so
as that mean write it down over here
每个K都有两个正常模式模式，我们可以称它们为Omega plus和minus ok，
each K has two normal modes modes we can
call them Omega plus and minus ok and
我们有多少个k，k的个数等于单位数
how many k's do we have the number of
k's are equal to the number of unit
单元，每个k有两个正常模式的两倍，所以正常模式的数量
cells and each k has two times two
normal modes so number of normal modes
正常模式的数量等于单位电池数量的两倍，并且它的销量等于
number of normal modes equals two times
number of unit cells and it sells equals
数量，这是我们应该期望的，因为我们有这个数量
质量是我们拥有的自由度的数量，所以当我们解决这个问题时
of masses is the number of degrees of
freedom we have so when we solve this
问题在于，有许多正常模式，而实际上我们这样做了
problem which is that exactly that many
normal modes and indeed we do so that's
这很好，我现在对所有的好都感到满意，因此对
that's good good I'm happy with that
all right good now so it's useful to
实际画出这个东西，我先将其勾画出来，然后我们将
actually plot this thing and I'm going
to sketch it out first and then we'll
某种理由说明为什么它看起来像这样做
sort of justify why it looks the way it
does
所以在这里我要在这里绘制K在这是Omega好的PI在
so here I'm gonna plot
here's K here's Omega okay PI over a is
负PI超过负PI，所以这是
minus PI over a minus PI over a so
that's the wrong zone outside of the
布劳恩斯拥有的一切都会重复，所以我们应该有一个像这样的模式
Brauns own everything just repeats so we
should have a mode that looks like this
然后更高频率的模式看起来像这样，然后您可以
and then a higher frequency mode maybe
looks like this okay and then you could
实际上定期在外部复制它，我的意思是你可以做到
actually reproduce this periodically
outside I mean you could you can make it
随心所欲继续前进，因为当您将所有PI移到两个PI上时
go onwards as you like because as you
shift everything by two PI over a you
只是回到同一波，但我们要真正专注于青铜
just get back the same wave but we're
gonna really focus on the bronze own
因为在这里拥有的青铜器中，您发现的每个波浪都与每个波浪不同
because within the bronze own here every
wave you find is different from every
另一波现在在这里看起来可能会有用
other wave now it's useful here to
probably look a little bit more
仔细查看此图，看看为什么它看起来像我绘制的样子，所以让我们
carefully at this plot and see why it
looks the way I've drawn it so let's
看一些方便的点，也许K等于零，这对
look at some convenient points maybe at
K equals zero that's a good point to
好好看看K等于0发生了什么，所以在这里我们有这个绝对值
look at well what happens with K equals
zero so over here we have this absolute
K 2加K 1 e等于i K等于K 2加K 1，所以M Omega平方是
K 2 plus K 1 e to the i ka that goes to
just K 2 plus K 1 so M Omega squared is
是K 1加K 2的2倍，或者是0，所以我在这里画出K处的0
either 2 times K 1 plus K 2 or at 0 and
so I've drawn that here here's 0 at K
等于0，这是较高的能量1可能能够吸收较高的能量
equals 0 and here is the higher energy 1
may be able to draw the higher energy
一个也因此Omega加K等于0是2的平方根1加Kappa 2
one also so Omega plus at K equals 0 is
square root of 2 capital 1 plus Kappa 2
我认为艾玛对这个观点的看法是对的，所以这里的要点是平方根
over Emma take it that right I think so
so that point here give it a square root
2的资本1加m的Kappa 2，所以我们有Loranger模式
of 2 capital 1 plus Kappa 2 over m and
we so we have the Loranger mode with the
高能模式现在低能模式我们将回到氢动力
high energy mode now the low energy mode
we will come back to the hydrogen motive
时刻，但低能量低频模式是我们应该期望的一种
moment but the low energy low frequency
mode is one that we should expect should
曾经去过那里，因为我们应该期望应该在某处有声波
have been there because we should expect
that there should be Soundwave somewhere
在系统中，当有声波时，我们注意到
in the system and when there are sound
waves we notice
具有在波矢量中具有线性频率的频谱的方法，以及
ways to have a spectrum which is has
frequency linear in wave vector and
现在以零波矢降到零，以说服自己，这就是
comes down to zero at zero wave vector
now to convince ourselves that's what's
继续这个方程，我们实际上需要做更多的数学运算
going on with this equation we have to
actually do a little bit of more math
并将色散曲线扩展到K等于零附近，让我们看看如何做到这一点
and expand the dispersion curve near K
equals zero so let's see how we do that
因此，让我们将K 2加K 1 e取到i ka那个数量是
so let's take K 2 plus K 1 e to the i ka
that quantity there is well yeah that
东西可以写成平方根Kappa 2平方加Kappa 1
thing there can be written as square
root Kappa 2 squared plus Kappa 1
ka的平方加2 kappa 1 kappa 2余弦
squared plus 2 kappa 1 kappa 2 cosine of
ka just by multiplying that out and if K
很小，我们将用1减去K乘以2的平方来代替余弦
is small we're going to replace this
cosine by 1 minus K a squared over 2 so
那么我们所拥有的就是我可以这样写它的平方根
then what we have is I guess we can
write it like this square root of this
整个Kappa 2加Kappa 1平方，当我放置时会照顾1个学期
whole thing Kappa 2 plus Kappa 1 squared
that takes care of the 1 term when I put
这个和这个加在一起，我得到Kappa 1加Kappa 2的平方，然后是什么
together this this and this I get Kappa
1 plus Kappa 2 squared and then what's
剩下的就是二元对消kappa 1 kappa 2 ka平方我得到我想要的
left over is the twos cancel kappa 1
kappa 2 ka squared I get that I want to
这样做是的，那么这很方便地分解出一个Kappa 2 plus Kappa
do that yeah ok then this conveniently
factors out to give a Kappa 2 plus Kappa
1的平方根加Kappa 1 Kappa 2 ka平方大写1
1 times the square root of 1 plus Kappa
1 Kappa 2 ka squared over capital 1
kappa 2平方，如果您还记得1的平方根加X oops负数
kappa 2 squared and if you remember
square root of 1 plus X oops negative
签错了他们签错了-那是-没有人拿到巧克力
sign wrong they got a sign wrong
that's - that's - no one gets chocolate
因为那是一个减去两个的x，所以我们可以将其重写为
for that is one minus x over two so so
then we have we can rewrite this as
卡伯2加资本一号-卡伯1卡伯2 ka
Kappa 2 plus Capital One - kappa 1 kappa
2 ka
平方乘以2个大写字母1加Kappa-
squared over 2 capital 1 plus Kappa -
我错过了什么吗？
does that look right did I miss anything
是的，kappa 1让我们加盖-谢谢kappa longo的kappa-是，是的，很好，谢谢
yeah kappa 1 let's cap - thank you kappa
Longo's kappa - yeah yeah good thank you
谁说我不是Michalka迟到的人，是的，好的，所以我没有
whoever said that I wasn't Michalka
late' yeah ok ok good so I don't have
今天我要带一个，但是我讨厌它，所以如果我插上那个
one today I was gonna bring one but I
hate it so alright so if I plug that
进入此处，我们看到大写字母1加Kappa-与-
into into here we see that the capital 1
plus Kappa - with the with the -
解决方案取消了此溶质，将资本金加Kappa取消-也将取消
solution cancels this solute this
capital 1 plus Kappa - also will cancel
这样，我们最终将得到em将使平方成为M Omega平方
this and we'll end up just getting em
will make a squared M Omega squared
等于资本1 kappa 2 ka平方2 kappa 1加Kappa-或等价
equals capital 1 kappa 2 ka squared over
2 kappa 1 plus Kappa - or equivalently
欧米茄是平方根kappa 1 kappa 2 a平方超过2 kappa 1加Kappa 2 em
Omega is square root kappa 1 kappa 2 a
squared over 2 kappa 1 plus Kappa 2 em
在那儿，然后绝对K没问题，我意识到这是很多数学
down there and then absolute K all right
and I realize that's a lot of math we're
今年不会做太多那么重的数学运算，但必须每学一次
not going to do too much math that heavy
this year but have to do it once in a
虽然很好，所以我们将其识别为声速，所以我们只是推导了
while okay so this we recognize as the
sound velocity so we just derived the
该波的声速声速是该曲线的斜率
sound velocity of this wave the sound
velocity is the slope of this curve here
现在通常我应该使用人们通常参考的适当术语
now usually actually I should use the
proper nomenclature usually people refer
以此作为声学模式
to this as the acoustic mode
他们倾向于称其为声学模式，甚至一直到该区域
and they tend to call it the acoustic
mode even all the way out to the zone
即使在K的情况下实际上只是声音
boundary out here at very high K even
though it's really only sound when it's
长，当它是长波长或小K时，它们在这里称为整个分支
long and when it's long wavelength or
small K they call the whole branch here
声学模式现在您还记得上一次我们导出声速时
the acoustic mode now you remember last
time when we derive the sound velocity
我们还能够通过使用氢获得相同的声速
we also were able to derive the same
sound velocity by using a hydrogen
原子参数，所以让我们看看这次是否可以再次执行此操作
atomic argument so let's see if we can
do that again this time remember from
在流体力学方面，我们认为V声在整个过程中应等于1的平方根。
hydrodynamics we have that the V sound
should equal square root of 1 over the
质量密度乘以可压缩性质量密度很好有两个
mass density times the compressibility
the mass density is well there are two
每个晶格常数a的质量和我们上次得出的可压缩性
masses per lattice constant a and the
compressibility well we derive last time
压缩系数应在弹簧常数乘以a和的基础上为1
the compressibility should be 1 over the
spring constant times a and the spring
这里的单元格中有两个弹簧，一个弹簧
constant well here the the unit cell has
two springs in it and the spring
两个弹簧串联的常数是kappa 1 kappa 2超过大写字母1 plus
constant for two springs in series is
kappa 1 kappa 2 over capital 1 plus
Kappa 2听起来很熟悉吗，记得从第一年起
Kappa 2 does that sound familiar
remember that from first year ok so if
我们把这个和这个和这个插入这里，实际上我们得到完全相同的结果V
we plug this and this and this into here
in fact we get exactly the same result V
声音等于平方根大写1 kappa 2 a平方超过2m的大写1加
sound equals square root capital 1 kappa
2 a squared over 2m of capital 1 plus
Kappa 2，因此流体力学计算可为您提供与我们完全相同的结果
Kappa 2 so the hydrodynamic calculation
gives you exactly the same result as we
通过完全解决系统问题得到的，现在让我们谈谈
got by actually solving the system
completely now let's talk about this
此处的模式与声学模式相比
mode up here this mode is known in
comparison to the acoustic mode this
模式在K时称为光学模式光学模式高频模式
mode is known as the optical mode
optical mode high frequency mode at K
等于0，我们可能应该说我应该告诉你为什么这个名字
equals 0 and we should probably I mean I
should probably tell you why the name
光学模式，因此“光学模式”一词来自真实实测
optical mode so the word optical mode
comes from experiments on on real real
当您在材料上照射光并引起振动时
materials when you shine light on the
material and you induced vibrations by
如果您想一想，现在就照耀着太阳
Sun by shining light on it now if you
think for a second what's the property
我们知道类似声光的频率为
of light that we know similar
sound light has frequency which is
与其波矢成比例，唯一的不同是C很大
proportional to its wave vector the only
big difference is that C is huge
与声速相比，如果我在同一条曲线上绘制光散射曲线
compared to sound velocity so if I drew
the light dispersion curve on the same
绘制一条非常陡峭的斜线，可能像这样陡峭
plot it would be an extremely steep
sloped line like this probably so steep
如果您想象材料上闪烁着光，我现在什至无法绘制它
I couldn't even draw it now if you
imagine shining light on a material and
在量子力学中产生振动，我们应该考虑吸收光子
creating vibrations in quantum mechanics
we should think about absorbing a photon
并创建一个声子，然后想象一个吸收光子和
and creating a phonon so imagine a
process where you absorb a photon and
创造一个声子为了做到这一点，你必须节约能量
create a phonon in order for that to
happen you have to conserve both energy
和动量，所以您必须同时匹配频率和波矢
and momentum so you have to match up
both the frequency and the wave vector
声子的波矢中具有频率的光的唯一位置
of the light with the frequency in the
wave vector of a phonon the only place
可能发生的事情就在这里，您永远无法匹配的原因
that can happen is right here and the
reason you're never going to match the
声模，因为速度失配非常严重，但与光学
acoustic mode because the velocity
mismatches so badly but with the optical
因为光学模式即使在K等于零时也具有有限的频率，所以存在
mode since the optical mode has finite
frequency even at K equals zero there is
光学模式频率与光频率和光学模式相匹配的点
a point where the optical mode frequency
matches light frequency and the optical
在这种情况下，模式动量与光动量甚至晶体动量匹配
mode momentum matches the light momentum
or even crystal momentum in this case
现在，这就是人们为什么称其为光学模式的名称
now so that's a nomenclature of where
why people call this the optical mode
每当您与光线和振动发生相互作用时，
whenever you have interactions with
light and vibrations it's inevitably the
光学模式，但我应该诚实地说我所描述的过程
optical mode but I should be a little
bit honest that that process I described
给你吸收光子而发出声子的方式实际上并没有
to you by which you absorb a photon and
you emit a phonon actually does not
发生而没有发生的原因是因为有一个保守的量子
occur and the reason it doesn't occur is
because there's a conserved quantum
编号光子的自旋，我的意思是光子具有自旋声子
number the spin of the photon which I
mean photons have spin phonons do not so
如果要发生该过程，则会违反角动量
if that process to were to occur you
would violate angular momentum
保护，所以您绝对不想破坏
conservation so that's you know
definitely bad you don't want to violate
保持角质素，因此实际上不存在这样的过程
angular mentum conservation so in fact
no such process exists by which a single
光子被吸收并产生单个声子，但是还有更多
photon is absorbed and a single phonon
is created however there are more
可能发生涉及光子和声子的复杂过程
complicated processes that can occur
involving photons and phonons for
例如吸收两个光子并发射一些声子，因为这个角度
example absorb two photons and emit some
phonons that's okay because this angular
两个光子的动量可以抵消，你可以
momentum of the two photons can cancel
and you can
我们将有保护，这仍然是很难克服的相同原则
we'll have conservation and it's still
the same principle that is very hard to
在声子与声子之间的任何形式的相互作用中均能保持能量和动量
conserve both energy and momentum in any
sort of interaction between phonons and
光子，除非您需要进入光学模式，因为您需要
photons unless you're getting optical
modes into the game because you need to
通过声子以某种方式使高频进入游戏，因此唯一的方法
get high frequencies into the game
somehow with phonon so the only way to
用声子的小波矢获得高频是使用光学
get high frequencies with small wave
vectors in phonons is to use the optical
模式好吧，所以这个名字实际上来自更普遍的地方
mode okay so that's where the name comes
from actually more generally
让我更一般地给Nam和Chur Chur讲声学模式
let me give more general Nam and clay
Chur here acoustic mode generally
声学模式是在小K且光与Omega成正比的任何模式
acoustic mode is any mode where Omega is
proportional to K at small K and optical
光学模式是欧米茄达到不等于常数的任何模式
mode optical mode is any mode where
Omega goes to a constant not equal to
在小K处为零好吧，让我们考虑一下这个小K体制
zero at small K okay let's think about
this this small K regime a little bit
更严重的是，我们发现本征值是频率，但让我们看一下
more seriously so we found the eigen
values the frequencies but let's look at
特征向量，所以我们实际上对角化的矩阵很大
the eigenvectors so the matrix we're
actually diagonalizing is that big
那里的矩阵，让我们看看它在K等于零，所以在K等于零
matrix there and let's look at it at K
equals zero so at K equals zero
我们感兴趣的矩阵的形式为
the matrix we're interested in is of the
form
我猜它是负Kappa 1加Kappa 2乘以1负1负1 1
I guess it's minus Kappa 1 plus Kappa 2
times what is it 1 minus 1 minus 1 1
那样的事情，还是我在错误的地方弄糟了，不，我想
something like that or do I get the
minuses in the wrong place no I think
没关系，所以看起来像这样，因为当波向量
it's right ok so it looks something like
this because when when the wave vector
变成0到i的指数e都变成1，所以你有一个矩阵
goes to 0 the Exponential's e to the i
ka both go to 1 and so you have a matrix
的形式是1 1减去1减去1 1（如果我拉出减去Kappa 1加Kappa 2）
of the form 1 1 minus 1 minus 1 1 if I
pull out minus Kappa 1 plus Kappa 2 so
特征向量我们有两个可能的特征向量
the eigen vectors
we have two possible eigenvectors one is
对于欧米茄等于零的解，我们有一个特征向量ax ay等于1 1
for the Omega equals zero solution we
have an eigen vector ax a y equals 1 1
至于光学模式解，另一个特征向量
where as for the the optical mode
solution the other eigen vector the high
能量高频本征向量，我们具有axay等于1减去1，所以
energy high frequency eigen vector we
have a x a y equals 1 minus 1 so what is
这告诉我们这是告诉我们的是对于k附近的声学模式
this telling us what this is telling us
is that for the acoustic mode near k
等于0，原子实际上正在与它们的邻居一起移动，
equals 0 the atoms are actually moving
with their neighbors that both of the
晶胞中的原子在同一时间向同一方向移动
atoms in the unit cell are moving the
same direction at the same time they're
同步移动，而对于光学模式，则为高频模式
moving in concert the whereas for the
optical mode the higher frequency mode
晶胞中的两个原子彼此相对移动，
the two atoms in the unit cell are
moving opposite each other and it's
实际上很自然地解释了为什么光学模式如此
actually quite natural to explain then
why it is that the optical mode is so
频率要高得多，因为在光学模式下，您正在压缩
much higher in frequency because in
optical mode you're compressing the
最大弹起，而当声学模式下您几乎没有压缩
springs maximally whereas when the
acoustic mode you're hardly compressing
之所以如此，是因为每个人都朝着相同的方向前进
the springs at all because everyone is
moving in the same direction these sort
趋势的发生更普遍，如果存在
of trends occur more generally so
general if if there are m
如果晶胞中的晶胞原子中有m个原子，我们将有M个模式
if there are m atoms in the unit cell
atoms in unit cell we would have M modes
在每个K处，声学就是每个人都以相同的方式运动的模式
at each K one is acoustic that's the
mode where every one moves in the same
K的方向等于零，则剩余的M减去其中之一为
direction at K equals zero and then the
remaining M minus one of them are
光学上的含义是，它们在k等于d时不等于0
optical meaning they don't all move in
the same direction at k equals 0 in d
维度d维度在香港d每k有d次m个模
dimensions d dimensions there are d
times m modes at each k at HK d our
光学声
optic are acoustic
剩下的D乘以M减去1可以算是好的，为什么这是我们
and the remaining D times M minus 1 are
optical okay why is this well we're the
模式的总数是指度数的总数
total count of the modes is a total
count of the number of degrees of
自由，如果有M，则每个K的数目总是与数字相同
freedom if there are M there's always
the same number of K's per as the number
系统中的每个单元格的每个每个值具有M质量
of unit cells in the system each each
value of each unit cell has M masses in
它可以在D维度上移动，因此共有DM自由度
it and they can move in D dimensions so
there's a total of DM degrees of freedom
每个单元格，因此我们期望每个K的DM模式现在可以有d个
per unit cell so we expect DM modes for
each K now of them there can be d of
他们在那里声学，并对应于任何一个
them there acoustic and that corresponds
to all of the masses moving in any of
三个可能的方向，所以我们知道我们已经讨论了这些事情
the three possible directions so we know
what these things are we've discussed
它们中的一个是纵向的，而其中两个是横向的，所以对于
them before one of them is longitudinal
and two of them are transverse so for
每一个K都向K方向移动，然后其中两个是
each K one of them is moving in the
direction of K and then two of them are
在三个维度上垂直于K移动好一点
moving perpendicular to K in three
dimensions okay there's one more point
在这张照片上，我们可能会更仔细地看一下
on this picture that we could probably
look at more carefully which is these
此处有趣的点位于所谓的Braun自己的边界PI
interesting points here near which are
at the so-called Braun's own boundary PI
让我把它放在这里，所以考虑考虑BZ边界BZ
over a let me put it over here so
consider consider BZ boundary BZ
边界K等于a上的PI，那么我们有什么好呢，那么这个系数Kappa
boundary K equals PI over a so what do
we have then well then this factor Kappa
i kappa 1的2加e实际上是绝对k2减去k1，所以
2 plus e to the i ka Kappa 1 is actually
absolute k2 minus k1 and so the
Ω平方的频率是m k1上的1加Kappa 1加Kappa 2正负
frequencies Omega squared is 1 over m k1
plus Kappa 1 plus Kappa 2 plus or minus
绝对Kappa 1减去Kappa 2或Kappa 2减去大写1并不重要
absolute Kappa 1 minus Kappa 2 or Kappa
2 minus Capital one doesn't matter its
绝对值，这意味着我们有两个可能的解决方案，欧米茄等于
absolute value and that means that we
have two possible solutions Omega equals
m上的2 kappa 1的平方根或2 kappa 2的平方根
either square root of 2 kappa 1 over m
or square root of 2 Kappa 2
在em上，因此我们将其标记在这里，因此该称呼2的平方根为1
over em so we'll mark them here so this
one will call square root of 2 capital 1
超过m，这个将称2为m的2 Kappa 2的平方根
over m and this one will call square
root of 2 Kappa 2 over m and here I've
假设资本1大于Kappa 2，否则更高
assumed that capital 1 is greater than
Kappa 2 otherwise around the higher
能量永远是最重要的，这些模式实际上永远不会相互交叉
energy one is always on top and these
modes actually never cross each other
您可以通过查看这些频率的形式来说服自己
you can convince yourself by looking at
the form of the the frequency that these
两种模式实际上无法交叉，所以在这个青铜器上发生了什么
two modes can never actually cross so
what's going on at this at this bronze
自身边界位于青铜器自身边界处，波形Delta X Delta y等于ax
own boundary at the bronze own boundary
the wave form Delta X Delta y equals ax
为什么将e代入IΩ减去负IK，再将这e代至负IK和a
a why e to the I Omega T e to the minus
I K and a this e to the minus I K and a
变成N的负1，这告诉我们发生了什么
becomes minus 1 to the N and that tells
us that what's going on is that
备用单位晶格彼此异相移动
alternate unit cells are moving out of
phase with each other they're moving in
彼此相反的方向，所以现在看看是否可以使它起作用
the opposite direction as each other so
now it's see if we can get this to work
哦，不，不，不，停止，停止，停止，停止
oh no no no stop stop stop sets of stop
没有
No
哦，亲爱的，这仅在星期一发生，所以我们在这里进行筛选哦，但是那是在
oh dear does this happen only on Monday
so here we go screen up oh but that's on
哦，哇，好极了，所以我们仍然可以在它进行的同时做这件事，所以这
oh wow amazing okay so we can still do
this while it's going on okay so this
程序是由Mike Glazer编写的，您可以单击交替
program is the thing written by by Mike
Glazer and you can click alternating
链条和纵向纵向意味着一切都在
chain and longitudinal longitudinal
means that everything oscillates in the
单行，您可以通过更改此滑块在此处更改K，您可以看到
single line you can change the K here by
changing this slider and you can see
色散在下方绘制，从零到2pi
that the the dispersion is plotted down
here it's plotted from zero to 2pi
而不是零而不是负PI超过零到2pi而不是a
instead of a zero instead of minus PI
over zero to 2pi over a instead of minus
我在这里画的像是2pi上的PI，所以它是同一张图片
PI over a 2pi over a like I've drawn
here so it's the same picture so first
让我们从非常小的K开始，哦，还有这些
let's start by taking K very very small
oh and also you have these little
咔嗒声在这里，这将改变弹簧的质量，让我们
clickers up here which will change the
masses on the springs let's make the
质量是相同的，而c1和c2或我们称之为两者的Capital One和Kappa
mass is the same and c1 and c2 or what
we call Capital One and Kappa to the two
弹簧常数，所以我们有两个不同的弹簧常数大写N和
spring constants so we have two
different spring constants capital N and
卡伯（Kappa）-这里是声学模式的分散，这里是光学模式
Kappa - and here's the dispersion the
acoustic mode down here the optical mode
在这里，我们单击了声学，所以我们实际上看到了声学模式
up here here we've clicked acoustic so
we're seeing actually the acoustic mode
在这里，您会看到声学模式的频率非常低，基本上
here and you see that the acoustic mode
is very low frequency and basically all
让我们将其向上移动一点，以便它可以更快地发生
of the let's move this up a little bit
so it happens a little faster you can
看到基本上所有的群众都在互相配合
see that basically all the masses are
moving in concert with each other sort
缓慢的来回晃动的水动力振荡
of slow sloshing back and forth
hydrodynamic oscillations you can sort
当您知道一个巨大的流体时，如果
of viewed as you know one big fluid
everything sort of moves together now if
我们去K等于零，它变成零频率，但我们可以在这里单击光学
we go to K equals zero it becomes zero
frequency but we can click on optic here
我们将得到光学模式，您会看到光学模式是每个质量运动的
and we'll get the optical mode you see
the optical mode is each mass moving
与晶胞中的其他质量相对，您可以看到这是
opposite the other mass in the unit cell
you can see that this is something that
应该是高频的，因为它现在最大程度地压缩弹簧
should be high frequency because it's
compressing the springs maximally now if
然后我们将K向量更改为bronz自己的边界，我们在这里是
we then change the K vector to the bronz
own boundary what we have here is is as
预测备用晶胞彼此相对移动，因此
predicted that the alternate unit cells
are moving opposite each other so this
单位质量，这两个质量与这两个质量相反，因此您可以
unit cell these two masses are moving
opposite of these two masses and you can
看看为什么它只是两个弹簧常数之一
see actually why it is
only one of the two spring constants
进入频率，因为这两个质量之间的弹簧实际上
enters in the frequency because the
spring between these two masses actually
完全没有压缩，只是晶胞之间的弹簧
isn't getting compressed at all it's
only the spring between the unit cells
被压缩，而不是晶胞内的弹簧
that are getting compressed and not the
spring within the unit cell that's
现在，如果您切换到压缩模式，请从以下位置开始压缩：
getting compressed now if you switch
then from looking at the optical mode at
区域边界到区域边界的声学模式看起来非常好
the zone boundary to the acoustic mode
of the zone boundary it looks extremely
类似，但这里的频率较低，但您会注意到这是另一个春天
similar but it's a lower frequency here
but you'll notice it's the other spring
现在被压缩了，仍然知道一个单元格正在移动
that's now getting compressed it's still
you know you have one unit cell moving
在一个方向上另一个单位晶格朝相反的方向移动，但现在
in one direction another unit cell
moving in the opposite direction but now
是相反的弹簧k2弹簧被压缩，而不是
it's the opposite spring the k2 spring
which is being compressed rather than
Kappa一个弹簧被压缩好了，所以我强烈建议人们
the Kappa one spring being compressed
okay so I highly recommend that people
下载此程序并弄乱它，还有很多其他乐趣
download this program and mess around
with it it's got a lot of other fun
这就是我们在无聊的星期六晚上可以做的事情或可以的事情
features this is what we can do on a
boring Saturday night or something okay
所以让我在这里重画这张照片，或者也许再停止一遍
so let me redraw this picture here or
maybe maybe stop this for a second okay
在这里重画这张图片好吧，我不知道为什么它仍然还在做
redraw this picture here all right I
don't know why it's still still doing
那好吧好吧，让我重画这张照片，除了我要
that but okay all right good let me
redraw this picture except I'm going to
略有不同，这里又是K，这是欧米茄，我要
draw slightly differently
here's K again here's Omega I'm going to
将PI放在此处，并将PI减去在此处，然后将两个PI放在此处和
put PI over a here and minus PI over a
here and then two PI over a here and
然后减去8的两个PI，我将绘制声学模式
then minus two PI over eight here I'm
going to draw the acoustic mode just
就像我以前拥有过的一样，然后我们以前拥有的光学模式是
like I had it before and then the
optical mode what we had before was
看起来像这样的东西，但我完全可以拿走这块
something that looked like this but I'm
perfectly allowed to take this piece
在这里，将其在a上移动两个pi，然后在此处进行绘制就可以了
here and shift it by two pi over a and
plot it instead here okay
所以我要做的就是拿走了这件作品，然后将它移了两个pi来移动它
so all I did was I took this piece and I
shifted it by two pi over a to move it
在这里，然后我可以在这里拿走这部分，并通过这种方式将其转移到PI
over here and then I can take this piece
here and shift it to PI over a this way
放在这里，所以现在我要抹去我认识的人
and put it here
so now I'm going to erase I know people
当您进行一系列转换时会讨厌中间的部分
hate when you do a race of transforms
going to raise the piece in the middle
我要把这些碎片留在这里
and I'm going to leave these pieces here
so this piece and have this piece
好吧，所以拿了这块，并以这种方式将它移动了2pi
okay so just took this piece and moved
it by 2pi over a this way and this piece
以2pi的方式移动，现在我以这种方式在这里得到这张照片
moved by 2pi over a that way and I got
this picture here now this way of
绘制事物被称为扩展区域游戏扩展区域方案，它
drawing things is known as the extended
zones game extended zone scheme and it
有一个很好的优点，就是只有一个凯，每个只有一个模式
has a nice advantage that there is only
one Kay there's only one mode at each
在h波向量k处的频率，因此在这里，每个波都有两种模式
frequency at h wave vector k so whereas
over here we have two modes at each wave
向量k在这里我们只有一个，但是我们使用了两倍的k范围，
vector k here we only have one but we've
used twice as much range of k and that
有时方便地做一些命名，这在此范围内很有用
sometimes convenient to to do just some
nomenclature which is useful this range
这里被称为第一个拥有自己的青铜器的青铜器，这里被称为该地区
here is known as the first bronze own
bronze own and this region here is known
作为这里的第二个青铜人，这里也是第二个青铜人
as the second bronze own along with this
region here second bronze own so we took
光学模式，我们将其从第一个青铜器中移出并放入
the optical mode and we moved it out of
the first bronze own and put it into the
扩展区域方案拥有的第二个青铜器，以这种方式画图
second bronze own for the extended zone
scheme this way of drawing things over
与扩展区相比
here
in comparison to the extended zone
该方案被称为减少区域方案，因为一切都已经
scheme is known as the reduced zone
scheme because everything has been
现在变成一个铜牌了，为什么这么方便
reduced into a single bronze own now why
is it that it's so convenient to to
展开所有东西，以便每个波矢处只有一个模式
spread everything out so that there's
only one mode at each wave vector well a
假设这样做非常有用的情况是以下情况
case where this becomes extremely useful
to do is the following case suppose
认为Capital One非常接近Kappa 2
consider Capital One very close to Kappa
所以在这种情况下，将会发生的是
so in that case what's going to happen
is that these this little gap here is
会变得非常小，所以让我们看看发生了什么
going to get extremely small so let's
see what that happened what that looks
就像这样，这里是K，这里是PI，而这里的PI是两个PI
like so here's K here's PI over a
there's two pi over a here's minus PI
超过a，而这里的负两个pi，因此
over a
and here's minus two pi over a so it's
看起来像是这样的，这样的缝隙很小
going to look like is kind of this that
like this like that so a very small gap
在这里是青铜的边界，因为首都一号和卡帕二号非常接近
at the bronze own boundary here because
Capital One and Kappa two are very close
现在彼此交流当Capital One实际上等于Kappa时会发生什么
to each other now what happens when
Capital One actually equals Kappa - well
那么我们所拥有的就是差距缩小，它变成了一条单独的连接线
then what we have is the gap closes it
becomes a single single connected line
但更重要的是我们恢复了单原子链
but more importantly we recover the
monatomic chain right
如果Capital One等于Kappa，那么每个质量和每个春天都是相同的
if Capital One equals Kappa - then every
mass and every every spring is the same
因为每隔一个春天每个质量都与每个其他春天相同，所以我们得到
as every other spring every mass is the
same as every other spring so we get
返回单原子链，但是晶格常数改变了新的晶格
back the monatomic chain but the lattice
constant has changed the new lattice
常数仅是旧晶格常数的一半，因为白色和
constant is only half as big as the old
lattice constant because the white and
现在黑球质量实际上是相同的，它们现在是相同的对象，所以我们
black ball mass is now actually are the
same they're the same object now so we
不必用两件事来制作一个晶胞，我们现在只用一个
don't have to make a unit cell with two
things we now make a unit cell with only
一件事是对的，所以棕熊拥有铜牌，而BZ现在的范围是K
one thing in it right so the Bruins own
the bronze own the BZ now ranges from K
是从负数从质数的PI变为质数好的PI，这是相同的
is goes from minus PI over a prime to PI
over a prime okay and that is the same
因为2 PI超过负2 PI超过2 2 PI超过了OK，所以这里的整个范围为1
as 2 PI over a minus 2 PI over a 2 2 PI
over a ok so this entire range here 1 if
这两个质量变得相同这整个范围成为第一个
the two masses become the same this
entire range here becomes the first
青铜拥有第一个单原子链的BZ，然后如果
bronze own first BZ of monatomic chain
monatomic chain and then if you make
Capital One和Kappa会使您在新产品方面稍有差距
Capital One and Kappa to slightly
unequal you open a small gap at the new
熊在PI上拥有自己的界限，但实际上底层是一个
Bruins own boundaries at PI over a ok
but really what's underlying is a single
从这里到这里，从这里到这里，单原子链的模式
mode for the monatomic chain from here
to here and here to here just a single
连接模式，当您将大写N和Kappa设为两个时，您将打开make
connected mode and you open up if make
when you make capital N and Kappa two
稍有不同，您会在自己的铜牌上开一个小缺口
slightly different you open up a small
gap at the bronze own at the bronze own
与新的较小的青铜合金的边界与新的较大的晶胞相关联
boundary with the new smaller bronze own
associated with the new larger unit cell
好吧，好吧好吧，在最后几分钟我想讨论一个完全不同的问题
okay happy okay in the last few minutes
I want to discuss a completely different
话题，我们没有，我们没到上次，那是我们的时间
topic something we didn't we didn't get
to last time which was our the time
在范德华（van der Waals）结合之前，您可能还记得这个家伙
before which is van der Waals bonding
van der waals you may remember this guy
根据您可能已经在统计中研究的范德华斯状态方程
from the van der Waals equation of state
that you've probably studied in a stat
机械范德华力键也称为分子键
mech van der Waals bonds also known as
molecular bonds molecular or fluctuating
偶极波动偶极键，这些是范德华键
dipole fluctuating dipole bonds bonds
and these are van der Waals bonds are
实际上与离子或共价或氢或
actually quite different from either
ionic or covalent or hydrogen or
金属键，从某种意义上说，这些键是针对非活性化学物而发生的
metallic bonds in the sense that these
bonds occur for inactive chemical
活跃物种中的物种，我所说的非活跃物种是
species in active species and what I
mean by inactive species is that no
电子在原子之间转移没有原子之间共享电子
electron is transferred between atoms no
electron is shared between atoms things
像稀有气体是范德华力键合的经典案例，稀有气体具有
like noble gases are classic cases of
Vander Waals bonding the noble gas has a
充满的外壳，它不共享电子，不捐赠
filled shell it doesn't share its
electrons it doesn't donate its
电子，它不共价键，它不
electrons
it doesn't covalently bond it doesn't
离子键，但它仍然可以范德华力键，这是另一个
ionically bond but it can still Van der
Waals bond now another example of an
非活性物质是分子，例如氮2本身就是一个原子
inactive species are molecules such as
nitrogen 2 nitrogen by itself as an atom
是非常活跃的，但是当您将两个氮原子放在一起时，它们会形成一个
is very active but when you put two
nitrogen atoms together they form a
极惰性的氮分子，您可以认为它是
nitrogen molecule which is extremely
inactive you can think of it as being
填充的分子壳的填充壳，一旦拥有，它也不会共享
filled shell of a filled molecular shell
and it also does not share once you have
分子分子非常稳定，不与电子共享
the molecule the molecule is very stable
it doesn't share its electrons with
其他什么也不会把电子捐给其他任何东西
anything else and it doesn't donate its
electrons to anything else so
尽管如此，即使您不捐赠电子或移动电子
nonetheless even though you're not
donating electrons or moving electrons
周围仍然可以用尽空间，但仍然可以形成一种纽带
around you can still running out of
space you can still form a bond the way
发生这种结合的情况如下，想像您说的是一个很好的稀有气体原子
the bond occurs is as follows imagine
that you have say a nice noble gas atom
在这里，也许还有另一个很好的稀有气体原子，我想
over here and maybe another nice noble
gas atom over here and I suppose at some
当亚当有一些偶极子向量p1 a时
moment the
Adam has some dipole vector p1 a
极化现在，如果您记得从您的enm离开R的距离，
polarization now if you remember from
your enm a distance R away there will be
由偶极矩引起的电场在这种情况下指向
an electric field due to that dipole
moment in this case pointing in that
方向和e在4个PI epsilon零R的立方上等于p1
direction and e will be equal to minus
p1 over 4 PI epsilon naught R cubed and
如果是我以不同的角度绘制角度，我便方便地选择R为
if it was if I had drawn the angles
differently I conveniently chose R to be
垂直于那一刻，但如果我不使它们垂直
perpendicular to the moment there but if
I didn't make them perpendicular there'd
是一些余弦，正弦之类的东西，像我现在要忽略的东西
be some cosines and sines and stuff like
that which I'm leaving out now when this
原子经历此电场会产生极化，并得到
atom experiences this electric field it
develops a polarization it gets an
感应极化P 2这是Chi恒定的时间e这是
induced polarization P 2 which is Chi
some constant times e this is this
常数在这里称为极化率极化率或
constant here is known as the
polarizability polarizability or
电敏感性
electric susceptibility electric
像氢这样的敏感原子，您可以计算出您知道的磁化率
susceptible atoms like hydrogen you can
calculate the susceptibility you know
微扰理论甚至可以将其作为运动
perturbation Theory maybe even done that
as an exercise as an exercise in the
他们要求你使用量子力学做到这一点
book they asked you to do that using
quantum mechanics
无论如何，现在我们有两个偶极矩，你会记得
anyway now what we have is we have two
dipole moments and you'll remember that
两个偶极矩的能量在4 PIε零R上为负P 1 P 2
the energy of two dipole moments is
minus P 1 P 2 over 4 PI epsilon naught R
求立方，这样总能量就可以将这些东西塞在一起
cubed so the total energy is then just
plugging these things all together
我们得到减去4个PI epsilon的负P 1平方PI零R将所有平方和
we get minus P 1 squared PI over 4 PI
epsilon naught R cubed all squared and
特别是这是负数，R等于第六，所以力等于1
in particular this is negative and goes
as R to the sixth so the force goes as 1
从R到第七，这或多或少是您如何计算的
over R to the seventh now that's more or
less how the calculation goes that you
具有一个原子的极化，它会引起另一个原子的极化，
have a polarization one atom it induces
a polarization in the other atom and
他们的两极分化很吸引人，但您可能会说，请等一秒钟
they the polarization is attract but you
might say well wait a second this whole
争论的依据是两极化不等于
argument was predicated on the statement
that the polarization is not equal to
从零开始，但在球对称原子上
zero to begin with but on a spherically
symmetric atom like
氦极化的期望为零为什么那么好
helium the expectation of the
polarization is zero why is that well
你还记得一个原子的极化这里是原子核这里是
you remember that the polarization of an
atom here's the nucleus here's the
电子以某种球形轨道绕原子运行
electron electrons running around the
atom in some sort of spherical orbit so
电子的位置R仅与极化有关
the position R of the electron is
related to the polarization just by
减去e乘以R或类似的数字，所以实际上我们只是在说
minus e times R or something like that
so it's really we're just saying that
电子的平均位置实际上是零，但是您会注意到
the average position of the electron is
actually at zero but you'll notice that
实际上，这个方程式不是极化或偶极子
what actually comes into this equation
is not the polarization or the dipole
矩P，但是它是P平方，所以P平方不等于零，所以你可以得到
moment P but it's P squared so P squared
is not equal to zero so that you can get
即使平均偶极矩为零，非零偶极引力
nonzero dipolar attractive force even
though the average dipole moment is zero
如果您想考虑一下，就知道波动和量子力学是
if you like to think about you know
fluctuations and quantum mechanics as
是某种动态波动或时间波动，
being some sort of dynamical fluctuation
or fluctuation in time what we really
意思是说，这是一种课程图或什么的粗略图
mean is that at it's a sort of a course
picture or a crude picture of what
量子力学是，但您可以将其视为某个时候
quantum mechanics is but you can sort of
think of it as at some moment in time
电子在原子核的一侧，所以有一个偶极矩
the electron is on one side of the
nucleus so there's a dipole moment the
另一个原子对此做出反应，而东方的偶极矩则相反
other atom responds to that and Orient's
its dipole moment in the opposite
方向，然后他们吸引，然后在以后的某个时间出现一个问题
direction then they attract and then at
some later time there's a question
是的，如果小便之间有角度，那是说如果有一个角度
yeah if there's an angle between pee
you're saying that if there's an angle
在p1到p2之间​​会有余弦Thetas等等，类似的东西
between p1 to p2 there would be cosine
Thetas and so forth and things like that
是的，但是在力量仍然具有吸引力的地方，实际上
yeah but that where the force will still
be attractive you can actually there's
书中有一个练习可以帮助您完成练习，并且您可以
there's an exercise in the book that
works you through it and you can and you
可以使所有角度正确，并且总是会出现有吸引力的好问题
can get all the angles right and it will
always come out attractive good question
但不值巧克力棒，所以还是个好问题，谢谢
but not worth the chocolate bar so but
it's still a good question thank you
无论如何，所以基本上你在一个原子上会有一点波动
anyway the so it's basically you get a
little bit of a fluctuation on one atom
它引起另一个原子的波动，它们吸引，无论是哪个原子
it causes a fluctuation the other atom
and they attract and no matter which
方向波动是响应波动在
direction the fluctuation is the
responding fluctuation is in the
相反的方向，他们总是吸引，所以你仍然可以得到一个非零
opposite direction and they always
attract so you can still get a nonzero
范德华力没有范德华力比共价离子弱得多
Van der Waals force no the van der Waals
force is much weaker than covalent ionic
或氢键，但它仍然足够强到可以引起诸如
or hydrogen bond but it's still strong
enough to cause important effects such
如您所知，它可以将低温下的氩气和
as you know you know it holds together
things like argon at low temperature and
当氩气变成固体时，范德华斯更有趣
when argon becomes a solid a more
interesting case of where van der Waals
如果你去过热带气候，部队就会和这个家伙在一起
forces show up is with this guy if
you've ever been to tropical climate
这是壁虎的小蜥蜴，他们也出售汽车保险
this this is a gecko a little lizard
they also they sell car insurance in the
美国我不知道为什么这是事实，这是美国的吉祥物
United States I don't I don't know why
that's true this is the mascot of the
壁虎Geico壁虎公司无论如何壁虎是惊人的小动物
Gecko Geico gecko company anyway
geckos are amazing little creatures
因为它们可以爬上几乎完全平坦的玻璃墙而没有
because they can crawl up almost
completely flat glass walls with no
根本没有麻烦，实际上把它们粘在墙上的东西变成了
trouble at all and the thing that
actually sticks them to the wall turns
成为范德华力，他们让你知道他们的脚很扁平，
out to be Van der Waals forces they have
you know they have very flat foot and
他们将脚踩在玻璃上，并且有足够的范德华力
they stick their foot onto the glass and
there's enough van der Waals force
在他们的脚和玻璃之间，它们是相当轻的小动物
between their foot and the glass and
they're fairly light little creatures
他们实际上可以走到墙上，因为那很好，我向我道歉
that they can actually walk up the wall
because of that all right I apologize I
过去了，我星期三见
went over it I will see you on Wednesday
you